Okay, I have gone back to the instant
project in cursor. So you can go to
file, new window, find your way to
instant. I'm back over here in instant
and I've closed down cambban. That's
gone. I've exited from the cambban
project. For me, I press the red button.
You can press the the X on Windows. And
here I am in instant. And I'm currently
in the instant directory. If I pwd, you
can see that I'm in user z projects
instant. I'm going to go up one cd dot
dot cdsp space dot and I'm now in just
my projects directory users ed projects.
And now I'm going to do something a bit
sad. I'm going to change I'm going to
rename our cambban directory. The way
you rename is you type mv which is short
for move. I'm going to change canban.
You do the the name the the previous
name canban. And I'm going to call that
instead cursor_anban.
Which means that that whole directory
has been renamed to something else.
Canban no longer exists. If I try and do
cdanban, I'll get an error. Look, no
such file directory can. Okay, it's
gone. And now and now, of course, I'm
going to to within the projects
directory, I'm going to do a get clone
and paste in the same old URL again. And
I've just brought in a new camb
directory with that single file
agents.mmd. So now we have a cursor
cambban which has that that whole thing
we just built. And now we have a fresh
camb directory which is uh just got the
one file in it. It's time now for us to
look at GitHub Copilot. So we are now
going to use GitHub Copilot which is a
fishly popular AI agent for coding. And
I'm looking here at GitHub's main
landing page and GitHub copilot is right
up there under platform. And you can see
if you go to plans and pricing that
there is a free tier which gets you a
certain number of requests a month
before you have to start paying. And so
for sure you can you can do this without
paying a scent. Uh and so there there
are various different ways that you can
use Copilot. You can use it in a command
line interface which we're not doing
this week. um you can use it through
through a sort of web front end as well.
But the most popular way and the way
that we will be doing it is using VS
Code, the open-source uh uh code editor
IDE that is so very popular and it's
going to look very familiar because as
it happens, Cursor is itself a a fork of
of this same editor, the same IDE. It's
also a VS uh VS code clone. Uh and so
it's going to look very very similar.
And that's what we're going to do. And
that means that the first thing we need
to do is install VS Code. So you may
already have VS Code, but if not,
there's right here conveniently there is
a link. Get it now. Uh over here, this
is where you can download it. This, of
course, is defaulting to Mac OS cuz it
knows I'm on that. There's also a
download button where you can download
it for your platform of choice, whatever
you are on. And you would then download
VS Code. If you already have VS Code,
you could do the check for updates to
make sure you got the latest version of
it. And once you've installed it and
opened it and probably answered a few
questions, but they should be very
standard stuff. I will see you over in
VS Code. Okay. And when you finally got
VS Code running, you may see a welcome
screen like this. You may see a
different screen. It doesn't really
matter, but it looks a bit different to
Cursor, but there's some some
familiarity over here. And the first
thing we're going to do is install an
extension. And you do that by going to
the view menu and selecting extensions.
It's also commandshiftx on a Mac or
control shiftx on a PC. I'll press that
now. Up comes the extensions marketplace
here. And you're going to type out
GitHub Copilot in there. You shouldn't
need to type it all out. Up will come
something and there should be a blue
install button. I don't have a blue
install button. Why is that? Because of
course I've already installed it. If I
click on it to make sure I've got the
right one, you can check that it's from
the verified github.com and I have 69
million downloads and you probably have
more. Uh, and and here we have it. This
is what it looks like. You should press
the blue install button in either place
and that will then put GitHub Copilot
into your VS Code. Okay. Next up, you go
to file, new window. Up comes this
screen. It looks a little bit different.
uh you go to open dot dot dot go and
find your projects folder find canban
again there it is go into canban press
open and now I'm going to make this a
bit bigger with command plus and I'm
going to resize this to fit the whole
screen so we are looking here at our
canban you can see the word canban is in
block capitals here it's at the title
here we know we're looking at the
cananban project in vs code so far so
good okay Next up, it's important to
sign in to GitHub if you're not already.
And the way that you do that is down
here on the bottom left. Click on the
avatar. And you can see that I'm signed
in to my GitHub account. And there
should be like a sign in right here. And
if there's not, then please check out
the course resources. If you have any
problems with this as people figure this
out, I will add in instructions to make
sure that everyone is clear on how you
connect to your GitHub account to use
GitHub Copilot. And when you are ready
and you've done that, you need to press
on a Mac it's commandshift I and on a PC
it's control shift I. I'm going to press
that now. And bam, a build with agent
appears over there on the right. And you
can also bring this up by going to the
view menu and selecting chat. That's the
same as control shift I or command shift
I. Okay. And so it's brought up this
sidebar that looks very familiar cuz
it's quite similar to cursor. And down
here you can see this is where we can
put an instruction to the agent. There's
a drop down here where we can choose to
put the agent in plan mode. Sounds
familiar. There is also this here where
we can choose what model we are
connecting to. I have it on auto where
it will pick one for us. But you can see
that there are also a bunch of models
that are provided for free in the in the
lowest tier plan. Depending on the
details of what plan you have, you may
have access to different models. And on
the the that topic, if you hover down
here, you'll see it pops up something
about how much you have been using
C-Pilot, which shows you a sort of bar
of what's been going on and shows you
what kinds of uh how how your usage is
against your allowance. And you can see
more details of that in the on the
GitHub Copilot website with the
different plans, the free and paid
plans, and how much you get. Okay, so
with that, that's the the just the quick
tour of the user interface. It's time
that we put our agent to work. Okay,
here we go. So, I'm putting the agent
onto plan mode and I'm going to say, uh,
no, please plan the task at hand.
Uh, it's got the agents.mmd and I'm
expecting it will pick that up. And it
has picked that up and it's off. And
it's off. It's gathered the context for
the canan project plan. So, I will let
it do some planning. Hopefully, yours is
as well. And I will see you in a second.
All right, the plan completed. As
before, there's some stuff here. It
seems like it might be interesting, but
I'm not going to read it. I'm going to
go ahead and press the start
implementation button. Uh you can you
can see here that there's a uh we could
continue it in the background, but we're
just going to have it run right here. Uh
I think we'll talk more about the cloud
services another time. And off it goes.
I sorry, sorry. Select that and then
start implementation appears in the
chat. And I press enter and off it goes.
So, I will let it do its thing, and I
will see you back here shortly. Uh, once
it's uh once it's it's made some
progress. Uh, but it is it is now going
to be prompting me to see if I want to
uh to allow. And you can see that we can
we can say always allow. We can just say
for now, I'm going to uh to allow this
one. So, I'm just going to press allow
right here. I'm going to let it go on
and do the next thing. And almost
immediately it's asking me if I it can
have permission to send no followed by
enter to the uh to the terminal. So
we'll let it do what it wants to do. Uh
and I'm going to keep uh approving what
it wishes while it does its thing. Uh
now what I might do is I might yeah I'm
just going to I'm just going to allow it
as as it goes and then uh at the right
time I will give it more permissions.
All right. Uh let's have a look at this.
It wants to run a command. Now what we
can say is we can say always allow. Um
and I'm going to say allow all commands
in this session. So this is this is like
a a yolo mode that we're going on to.
Let it do its thing. I'm going to be
watching carefully. You should choose
the level of risk you're comfortable
with. You can have it be approving step
by step as you want so that you could
watch what happens. But I will let it do
its thing and I will see you back in a
second. Okay. Okay. Well, in the spirit
of not only showing you when things go
well, this time it seems to be
struggling a bit in a way, it just tried
to bring up it did a lot of coding. I
needed to approve another thing that it
that it still needed me to approve. Um,
and then it had a few bugs that it
fixed. Uh, and then and then it tried to
start the server and first of all it
started it in the wrong directory and
got a bunch of of errors and then it
figured that out and it changed to the
right directory, started the server
again and then it it ran a command to
bring the server up and it's just been
sitting there waiting not realizing that
the server has come up. It's kind of
jammed and I guess it wants me to to uh
I going to have to interrupt it by by by
cancelling right here and stop it from
thinking. But there is something of a
surprise here which which I will reveal
after stopping it. Okay. So here we go.
I I will indeed stop it. Done. It has
stopped. Uh and now uh and now to show
you the uh the surprise. So here's the
surprise. I'm I'm going I'm here in the
terminal. I'm in the front end directory
and I can do mpm rundev which is the
command to start the server. And if I do
that it brings up a server. And if I now
go to that web address, uh you can see
that it's actually it's done a really
good job. It's finished. Uh even though
it sort of it floundered at the very
last minute, it seemed to get stuck. Um
but what we have here, of course, is a
canban. It's got quite a nice layout.
And the way that you can move things
around, I actually rather prefer this to
the one that we got from cursor. I
happen to I believe that that we've been
using through through the GitHub
copilot. been using uh Claude Haiku a
very small model but I think it's done a
fabulous job you can see we can move
things around the drag and drop seems to
work great and uh I think this is this
is a pretty good implementation unlike
the one that we got from cursor we don't
have any errors showing here let's try
deleting to see if it will delete oh no
look at that delete is not working
that's one that's one bug can we rename
this to okay yes we can rename the
columns all right so uh you know it's
most of the way there not bad at all.
Not bad for for its first pass, even
with the hanging at the end. And we'll
give it a chance to try and fix that
problem that it's made. Let's come back
over here. Just here where it says files
changed, we press keep to make sure that
we keep anything that is uh that has
been uh affected. Um and let's stop the
server. And let me just say in here um
uh everything
seems to be working well
to be working well
except I uh the delete
card feature
isn't working.
Let's give it that feedback. Let's see
how it does with this. Uh and uh we will
give it a chance and I will come back in
just a second. Okay. Well, it believes
that it's fixed it. Uh, the delete card
feature should now work. Now, this shows
me it's it's an interesting sign,
particularly with some of the smaller
models. What I dislike about this is
that it has done a classic move by
coding agents, which is to guess what it
thinks the problem is, put in a fix, and
then claim victory. And that's just
riddled with problems. First of all, it
shouldn't guess. It should prove the
problem. If it thinks it has a theory,
we would always want it to prove it. And
secondly, it shouldn't just fix
something and say it's fixed without
testing and demonstrating. It needs to
reproduce an issue, prove the root
cause, fix it, demonstrate it's fixed,
and it should always do that. And when
you're watching this, particularly if
you're somewhat new to to uh to
development, then you need to be the
boss of that process. You need to push
back and challenge even if it has it
right. And I don't know if it has it
right. We will we will give it a try now
and see if it actually got it right.
Okay. So, I do mpm rundev to bring up
the server. Uh, there it is. Here is my
screen. And there we go. Let's try
deleting.
Just as I thought. No change at all. If
it hasn't proven the problem, then it
probably doesn't work. So, that that
didn't work. Let me just check if I
press keep here that that doesn't change
anything. But I I don't think so. That
that that won't change anything at all.
Um, and in fact, we now do see an issue
appearing here. Uh, okay. All right. So,
um, I will keep hammering away at it.
We'll tell it. I'll give it strictly the
feedback that that didn't fix it. And
I'm going to tell it. So, I say that
didn't fix it. Please, first reproduce
the problem
and prove you've reproduced it.
Find the root cause.
Fix it.
and prove you fixed it.
That's that's how to give it
instructions to do this in a disciplined
way and you have to take it through that
process. Uh okay. And I will I will
allow it to do its thing and uh as it as
it looks in the in the web page and I
will see you again in a second. Okay. It
now claims it has reproduced the
problem, fixed it and implemented a fix
and tested it. We will be the judge of
that. Here we go. It's running. The
server is running. I bring this up. I
come in here. I press delete and indeed
it has fixed it. Excellent. And I think
that this was fortuitous, very very
convenient because I think it's a really
important learning point about first of
all not believing it when it tells you
it's found the problem and fixed it. And
secondly, giving it those specific
instructions. Reproduce the problem.
Prove the root cause. Fix it.
Demonstrate that you fixed it. That's
the right recipe for success with
debugging. Okay. Onwards.